EPHRAIM MATARUTSE

63-2059744K80

ephraimmatarutse@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ephraimmatarutse

Carrer Object

To grow my abilities in the specialized areas of Software programming, Customer Service, Computer Programming, Networking, Database Management and Web Designing, and any other area of IT. To leverage and integrate my skills which will add significant value to organizational operations as well as global industry at large.

Version Control: Git
 React: Hooks, Redux
 MySQL: Queries, Indexing
 Next.js: SSR, API Routes
 Data Analysis
 MongoDB: NoSQL, Mongoose
 JavaScript: ES6, DOM:

 Python: Django, Flask
 Results Oriented

EDUCATION

University Of Zimbabwe, Mt Pleasant, Harare

AUGUST 2023

Bachelor of Computer Science

Degree Class 2.2

PROJECTS

E-commerce Website with React and Express.js

Community Pharmacists Association Zimbabwe Website with Next.js

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Computer Science Attachment

Chitungwiza Central Hospital, Chitungwiza, Harare MAY 2020 - MARCH 2021

- Network Configuration: Configured and maintained network for a reliable, secure hospital infrastructure.
- SAP Module Expertise: Optimized SAP modules for efficient hospital operations and data management.

Sales & IT Personnel

Wholelight Trading, Eastlea, Harare

OCTOBER 2022 - AUGUST 2023

- Technical Troubleshooting: Offered tech support, promptly resolving product issues with effective troubleshooting.
- Sales Achievement: Consistently achieved and exceeded monthly sales targets, significantly contributing to the company's
 overall success.

Full-Stack Developer

ZimInd Publishers, Graniteside, Harare

AUGUST 2023 - NOW

- Newsletter Deployment: Deployed newsletters on a daily basis, managing content delivery and engagement.
- Web Application Development: Created, maintained responsive web apps in Python, JavaScript for seamless UX.

LEADERSHIP AND ACTIVITIES

• Active Member, LEO Club, Hartzell High School

FEBRUARY 2015-2016

Engaged Participant, Science Club, Hartzell High School

FEBRUARY 2015-2016

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- HEXCO Computer Operations and Packages
- ALX Software Engineering Program
- Programming Hub Django, React, CSS & C Programming

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages

English & Shona

Hobbies

- Traveling: Exploring new cultures and experiencing diverse environments.
- Gaming: Strategic and casual gaming for relaxation and mental stimulation.
- Playing Cricket: Passionate about the sport, fostering teamwork and camaraderie.